I am both a prince
私は皇子です
And a subject
臣でもある
How could there be
どうしてあるのですか
Reason to disobey orders?
指示に従わない理由
This is my military seal
これは私の虎符軍印です
I give it to General Chen
陳将軍に委ねる
I hope General Chen
陳将軍にもお願い申し上げます
Will fulfill his duties diligently
職務を注意深く遂行する
Do not disappoint the soldiers
どうか将兵たちを裏切らないでください
Please rest assured, Your Highness
どうか殿下ご安心ください
I
しん
Will not disappoint Your Highness
必ず殿下のご期待に応えます
He's so obedient
彼はただ素直に従っているだけだ
Just handed over military command like that
そのまま兵権を渡してしまった
In my heart
私の心の中は
I'm uneasy
不安だな
A dog that bites
人を噛む犬
Never barks
全く鳴かない
In the past
昔日せきじつ
When Prince of Jin was imprisoned
晋王が投獄された時
I advised Your Highness
私はかつて殿下に助言したことがあります
To go all the way
中途半端にやらず徹底的にやる
But Your Highness then
しかし殿下その時
Hesitated
しかしためらった
Chancellor Chen
陳相
Don't tease me
私をからかわないでください
Give the order
命令してください
Immediately order Qingzhou Army to break camp
慶州軍に直ちに駐屯地を撤収するよう命じる
Move toward the capital
皇城に近づく
Also
まだ
Send Chen Ying
チェンインへ
Another letter
もう一度手紙を送る
Yes
はい
This is just my personal letter
これはただの私の家書です
Why was it opened?
なぜ人に壊されたのですか
General Chen Ying ordered
陳応将軍の指示
All correspondence in the army
軍中のあらゆる文書のやり取り
Must first be sent to him for review
まず彼に確認してもらうために提出しなければなりません
Chen Ying
チェンイン
Think clearly
よく考えてください
Whose orders do you follow?
あなたは一体誰の命令を聞いているのですか
I only follow military orders
末将はただ軍の命令に従います
Who promoted you all this way?
今までの道のりで誰があなたを引き上げてくれたのですか
I really misjudged you
私は本当に人を見誤ったようだ
Get out
出かける
Your Highness
殿下でんか
Let's have a good drink tonight
夜にたくさん飲んで楽しんでください
Sir
大人
The volunteer army families
義軍の家族
All depend on Yiyang's compensation to survive
すべては弋陽の救済にかかっている
Really can't delay any longer
本当にこれ以上遅らせることはできない
Want to talk? Fine
話したいならいいよ
After you're cleaned up
後で洗ってきれいにしておく
The heir
世子
The princess consort
王妃
Are both in the capital
みんな京にいる
I must consider them
私は彼らのことを考慮しなければなりません
Right now, no matter what
今はどうしても
Cannot act rashly
勝手に触ってはいけない
Who?
誰
Your Highness
殿下でんか
It's me
私です
Zhu Yuanzhi
朱元之
What are you doing?
何をしているの
At this time
こんな時
You kill Chen Ying's men
あなたは陳応を殺した人です
Isn't that making things worse?
まだ大事だと思わないの
Your Highness
殿下でんか
Look who's here
誰が来たか見てごらん
This old minister
老臣ろうしん
Finally sees you
ついにあなたに会えました
Please rise quickly
早く起きてください
Huiji is a thousand li
会吉は弋陽に向かう
From Yiyang
千里の彼方
How did you come?
どうして来たの
Since Your Highness's victory
殿下がご勝利を得られて以来
The situation has been crystal clear
情勢は手に取るように明らかである
So I
そこで臣
Left Huiji Commandery early
早々に会吉郡から手を引く
Secretly returned to the capital to plan
京への密かな配置
Your Highness
殿下でんか
This is what I intercepted from the capital
これは私が京城から入手したものです
A secret letter from Chen Dao to Chen Ying
陳監督が陳應に送った秘密の手紙
This is critical
重大な問題に関わる
Quickly summon Xie Xuan
あなたは早く謝玄を連れて行ってください
And Uncle Qiu together
丘叔と一緒に呼び出す
Zhu Yuanzhi, how dare you
朱元之君は大胆だ
My sister and the heir are still in the capital
私の姉と世子はまだ京にいますか
Are you trying to harm them?
あなたは彼らを害そうとしているのですか
Brother-in-law
義兄
Don't be impulsive
衝動的にならないで
Father
父
Say something
何か言ってよ
Your Highness
殿下でんか
Though somewhat offensive
少し失礼かもしれませんが
I must speak some words
しかし私にはどうしても言わなければならないことがあります
If Your Highness hesitates further
もし殿下がさらにためらうと
Then we'll be like fish on a chopping block
それなら刀の上のまな板として待つしかない
At others' mercy
私は魚肉のために
Enough, Zhu Yuanzhi
もう十分だ朱元之
Do you know what you're saying?
あなたは自分が何を言っているか分かっていますか
I know Your Highness's concerns
私は殿下のご懸念を理解しています
But if Your Highness truly dies here
しかし殿下もしあなたが本当にここで亡くなるなら
Then the princess consort
その王妃
And the heir
和世子
Can they have a good outcome?
彼らは幸せな結末を迎えられるのでしょうか
Your Highness
殿下でんか
Strike first to gain advantage
先に動いた者が勝つんだ